Guide to the Charlotte Beers papers, 1958-2013 and undated RL.11767
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charlotte Beers papers
1958-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Beers, Charlotte
RL.11767
11.0 Linear Feet
Charlotte Beers is an advertising executive, author and diplomat based in Chicago, New York and Charleston, South Carolina. Collection includes clippings, correspondence, book manuscript drafts, presentations and speech scripts, memos to and from David Ogilvy, transcripts of interviews and other printed materials as well as audiovisual materials (videocassettes and optical disks) that document Beers' career in advertising and her tenure as Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs. Institutions represented in the collection include American Express, J. Walter Thompson Company, Ogilvy & Mather, Tatham-Laird & Kudner, the U.S. State Department and the 9-11 Commission. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Book Files; Ogilvy & Mather; Presentations; Tatham Laird & Kudner; U.S. Department of State; and Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Charlotte Beers is an advertising executive, author and diplomat based in Chicago, New York and Charleston, South Carolina. Born 1935, Texas. Baylor University 1957 (math and physics). Teacher, Alvin Jr. High School 1958. Statistician, Humble Oil 1959. Researcher, Uncle Ben's 1960-1968. Account executive and Senior Vice President, J. Walter Thompson Chicago, 1969-1978. Chief Operating Officer, Chief Executive Officer and Chairman, Tatham-Laird & Kudner 1979-1992; CEO and Chairman, Ogilvy & Mather 1992-1999. Chairman, J. Walter Thompson New York 1999-2001. Undersecretary of State 2001-2007. Board of Directors, Martha Stewart Omnimedia 2008-2013. Chairman, American Association of Advertising Agencies 1987-1988. Awards: National Advertising Woman of the Year 1975; Advertising Women of New York Lifetime Achievement 1997; AAF Hall of Fame 2008.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Provenance
The Charlotte Beers papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Anthony Weir papers
Helayne Spivak papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising vertical file
Jock Elliott papers
Joel Raphaelson papers
John R. Blaney papers
Kenneth Roman papers
Ralph Rydholm papers
Reva Korda papers
William E. Phillips papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes clippings, correspondence, book manuscript drafts, presentations and speech scripts, memos to and from David Ogilvy, transcripts of interviews and other printed materials as well as audiovisual materials (videocassettes and optical disks) that document Beers' career in advertising and her tenure as Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs. Institutions represented in the collection include American Express, J. Walter Thompson Company, Ogilvy & Mather, Tatham-Laird & Kudner, the U.S. State Department and the 9-11 Commission. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Diplomacy -- 20th century; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Women in the advertising industry; American Express Company; J. Walter Thompson Company; Ogilvy & Mather; Ogilvy, David, 1911-1999; United States. Dept. of State
- General Files, 1973-2013 and undated; 1
  - Advertising Hall of Fame, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Article--Adweek, 1985 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Charlotte Beers: Lean Machinist (William Meyers)
  - Article--New York Times, with correspondence and responses, 1985; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Pushing Tatham Closer to the Top (William Meyers)
  - Beers' park party, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Biographical material, 1975-2007; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings--AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies), 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - CMO Perspectives, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Dartmouth College Executive in Residence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Day books, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Harvard Business School, 1999-2005 (Box 1)
  - Housewarming party, 1993; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Invitations, stationery, undated (Box 1)
  - J. Walter Thompson, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Journal (with story of firing), 1995 (Box 1)
  - Leazding Authorities--Presenting a New Way to Look at Meetings, 2008 (Box 8)
  - Memos and miscellaneous, 1992-1996 and undated (Box 1)
  - Mirabella 5th anniversary, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Move to New York, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Notes, 1993-2008; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1980-1997 and undated; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs--AWNY (Advertising Women of New York) Lifetime Achievement, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Photographs--Deborah Feingold, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Photographs--Star Black, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs--Victor Skrebneski, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1989-2012; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1987-2007; 2 folders (Box 8)
    In English and French
  - Publicity, 1985-2013; 3 folders (Box 9)
    In English and Spanish
  - Residence, East End Ave, NY, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Residence, East End Ave, NY, 1994 (Box 9)
    Blueprints of rose garden area
  - Residence, Garden Room in Charleston, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Slide shows, undated (Box 1)
  - Speeches and clippings from JWT Archive at Duke University, 1973-2001 (Box 1)
  - Robert Tichid--Kelly O'Dea: Building Alliances for the Next Economy, 2005 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Professionals Conference, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Video log, notes, undated (Box 1)
- Book Files, 1995-2010 and undated; 2
  - Brand Stand book proposal, 2009; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Brand stories, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Breaking the Brand writing samples, 2008 and undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Breaking the Brand writing samples, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Cases, stories, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
  - Chapter III: Tatham, Horse of a Different Color 1985-1988, undated (Box 2)
  - Chapter XIII: Into the War 1992, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Defeating the retirement plan, undated (Box 2)
  - Draft versions, 2008; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Early writings, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Female in the Boardroom proposal, undated (Box 2)
  - First jobs, first impressions, lasting impace, undated (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Wonderful, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Wonderful stage 2, undated (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Wonderful stage 2, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Know thyself, undated (Box 2)
  - Manuscript draft binder, 1998-2007 (Box 2)
  - New women at work, undated (Box 2)
  - Notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Notes, introduction draft, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Ogilvy mid-life crisis, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
  - Ogilvy stage 1, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Ogilvy stage 2, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Ogilvy stage 3, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Roles we play, drafts and versions, 2004-2010; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Rough versions of units, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Simple is harder to do, undated (Box 3)
  - Tools of the trade, undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Website for book, undated (Box 3)
  - Well, what is the job?, undated (Box 3)
  - What matters?, undated (Box 3)
  - Winning Women book proposal, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Washington DC chapter, undated; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - You never get a second chance to make a first impression, undated (Box 3)
- Ogilvy & Mather, 1958-1997 and undated; 3
  - Adweek Agency of the Year, 1995 (Box 3)
  - American Express, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - American Express--Aldo Papone, 1994 (Box 3)
  - American Express--Brand presentation, 1993 (Box 3)
    Includes Honda case study
  - Annual report, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Arrowwood action plan, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Arrowwood conference, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Barnard College--Iphigene Ochs Sulzberger Award, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Baylor University--Beta Gamma Sigma Award presentation, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Booz Allen and Hamilton presentation, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Brand audit, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Brand audit of clients, 1993 (Box 3)
    Includes: American Express, Book of the Month Club, Dove, Four Roses, Latta, Lufthansa, Maxwell House, Molson, Perrier, Pond's, Ryder, Sears
  - Brand presentations, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Brand Steward's Handbook, undated (Box 3)
  - Brand Stewardship, 1992-1997; 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Brand Stewardship examples, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Brand Stewardship Master Class, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Brand Stewardship presentation, slides, 1997-1998 and undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Branding, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Building a Brand from Scratch, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1992-1996; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Congratulatory letters (appointment to CEO), 1992; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - David Ogilvy creative desk file, 1975-1983 and undated (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy--How to Create Good Advertisements, 1958 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy dinner, 1995 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy meeting, 1992 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy memorial, 1999 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy--Principles of Management, 1970 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy--Speech to Kraft, 1993 (Box 4)
  - David Ogilvy--We Sell or Else, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Dorothy Sarnoff Speech Dynamics, undated (Box 4)
  - Dove--How to Use Your Brandprint, undated (Box 8)
  - End of year memo, 1995 (Box 4)
  - European Directors meeting, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee, 1995; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Ford meeting, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    Includes Coke and Jaguar case studies
  - Global Vision publication, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Harvard case studies, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Harvard WPP case study, 1996 (Box 4)
  - How to Create Advertising that Sells, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Investors' presentation, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Kodak meeting, 1995 (Box 4)
    Includes Coca-Cola Brandprint presentation
  - Kraft brand presentation, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Latin American Heads of Office meeting, 1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Letterhead, undated (Box 4)
  - Memos, 1992-1997; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Memos from David Ogilvy, 1991-1995 and undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Memos to David Ogilvy, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
  - Mission statement, undated (Box 4)
  - National Sales and Marketing Hall of Fame, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Nestle, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Norman Berry: Some Things I've Learned and Some Things I Believe, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Notes and miscellaneous, 1984-1992 (Box 4)
  - O&M Direct, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Paris visit, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Philip Morris brand stewardship meeting, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Presentation binder, 1996-1997; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Publicity, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Roger Makin Brand Print, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Sara Lee Frontrunner Award, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Senior Partner meeting, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Shell meeting, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Shelly Lazarus--Where Brand Stewardship Leads, 1997 (Box 5)
  - South Africa agency image study, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Thirsty for Change original team, undated (Box 5)
  - Three Chances to Hit a Home Run, undated (Box 5)
  - Transcript, undated (Box 5)
  - Transcripts of Beers' talks, undated (Box 5)
  - Unpublished David Ogilvy, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Vision Project, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - What We Believe and How We Believe (corporate culture statement), 1990 (Box 9)
  - Worldwide Board of Directors, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Worldwide Plaza, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Worldwide strategy, 1993; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - WPP Analysts meeting, 1996 (Box 5)
- Presentations, Speeches, 1979-2013 and undated; 4
  - AAAA annual meeting, 1988 (Box 5)
  - AAF (American Advertising Federation) Raleigh-Durham, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Account Executives: What Do You Do for a Living?, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Adcraft, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Addy Awards, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Advertising Women of New York, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Advertising Women of New York awards luncheon, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Adweek Summit, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Agenda for presenting Female in the Boardroom, 1996 (Box 5)
  - American Academy of Achievement, 1996 (Box 5)
  - American Bankers, undated (Box 5)
  - Association of National Advertisers (ANA), 1992-1997; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Boehringer Ingelheim Pharmaceuticals, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Brand management talk (Eyepatch), 1996 (Box 5)
  - Brand Stand: A Master Class in How to Brand Yourself, undated (Box 5)
  - Brand Stand proposal binder, undated (Box 5)
  - Business Week Symposium, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Catalyst Awards, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Center for Women, undated (Box 5)
  - CFTA speech, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Chicago Advertising Federation, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Chicago Network, 1995 and undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - CNN/CNBC blog, 2011 (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Club of Charlottesville, 2013 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1997-2012 (Box 5)
  - CXO Media, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Direct Marketing Association, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Ernst & Young Professional Women's Forum, 2012 (Box 5)
  - Forbes talk, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Fuqua Association of Women in Business, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Harvard Business School, 2010 (Box 5)
  - High Performance Organizations, 1997 (Box 5)
  - IBM, 2008-2010 (Box 5)
  - Institute for International Research, 2006 (Box 5)
  - International Women's Association, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Invest in Your Future conference, 2012 (Box 5)
  - Iowa Women's Leadership Conference, 2012 (Box 5)
  - JWT book party, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Kantar Mentoring for Success, 2013 (Box 6)
  - Lockheed Women's Leadership Forum, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Magazine Publishers Association, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Massachusetts Conference for Women, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Matrix Award, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 2006-2008 (Box 6)
  - Oracle Women Leaders, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Phoenix Women's Leadership Conference, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Pot and Kettle, undated (Box 6)
  - Raytheon Leadership Forum, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Relationship Between Client and Agency, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Retail Advertising and Marketing Association, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Rotman School of Business, 2013 (Box 6)
  - Sermon, St. Chrysostom Church, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Show Biz Conference, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Skyforum, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Speech idea file, 1985 and undated (Box 6)
  - Speeches, 1995-2007; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Strategic Leadership Forum, 1997 (Box 6)
  - TedX, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Texas Conference for Women, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Transperfect Translations, 2007 (Box 6)
  - Treasury Women 3.0, 2012 (Box 6)
  - United Way of Atlanta, 2004 (Box 6)
  - University of Chicago Graduate School of Business Career Planning Conference, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Washington PR Woman of the Year, 2012 (Box 6)
  - Why Can't a Woman Be More Like a Brand?, undated (Box 6)
  - Winning Women, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Women Impacting Public Policy (WIPP) Leadership Conference, 2013 (Box 6)
  - Women in Communication, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Women's Ad Club of Chicago, 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Women's Leadership Exchange, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Yale School of Management, 2005 (Box 6)
  - YWCA of Charleston Tribute to Women of Influence, 2006 (Box 6)
- Tatham Laird & Kudner, 1982-1992 and undated; 5
  - Bush/Quayle re-election campaign, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Charlotte Beers birthday card, undated (Box 6)
  - Clippings, 1983-1992; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Congratulatory letters (appointment to CEO), 1982 (Box 6)
  - Documents, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Evergreen Bonus Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 6)
  - Ford Future presentation notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Jean-Michel Goudard (RSCG) merger proposal, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 6)
  - Profits, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Publicity, 1984-1992; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Resignation, 1992; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - RSCG merger, 1987-1992; 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Script of book chapter, 1986 (Box 6)
  - William Ross, 1983-1986 and undated (Box 6)
- U.S. Department of State, 2001-2007 and undated; 6
  - 9/11 Commission hearings, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Clippings, 2002-2007 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 2002-2007 (Box 7)
  - Council on Foreign Relations--A New Beginning, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Counterterrorism newsletter, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Notes, undated (Box 7)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 7)
  - Presentation to House Committee, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Press releases, 2001-2004 (Box 7)
  - Private Sector Summit on Public Diplomacy, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Publicity, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Rapid Response newsletter, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Shared Values Project, 2003; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - State Magazine--Colin Powel: Finishing Our Work in Iraq, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Strategic direction, undated (Box 7)
  - Tim Isgitt remarks at Beers' farewell reception, undated (Box 7)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1992-2013 and undated; 7
  - Advertising Council dinner reel, 16:00, 1994 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-001)
  - Bradshaw on the Family, Part VIII: Help for the Family, 60:00, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-002)
  - Bradshaw on the Family, Part IX: Health for the Family, 60:00, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-003)
  - Career Camp Bites, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-004)
  - Charlotte Beers: ABC 3/4, Fox News 3/5, NBC 3/6, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-005)
  - Charlotte Beers: ABC 3/4, Fox News 3/5, NBC 3/6, copy 2, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-006)
  - Charlotte Beers resign: ABC 3/4, Fox News 3/5, NBC 3/6, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-007)
  - CMO 2005 Charlotte Beers session (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-008)
  - Family for Xmas, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-009)
  - Foreign Press Center Briefing: Charlotte Beers and Richard Boucher, "Public Diplomacy in Support of the International Coalition" 1:07, 2001 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-010)
  - Fortune Conferences, Most Powerful Women in Business: Charlotte Beers, 30:00, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-011)
  - Frontline: Trail of Terrorists, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-012)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Changing Your Life/Charlotte Beers; Good Morning America, 4:22, 1999 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-013)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Charlotte Beers Every Woman interview, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-014)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Good Morning America, 1999 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-015)
  - Leading Authorities--Charlotte Beers speech presentation, 2004 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-016)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Advertising on Ogilvy, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-017)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Advertising on Ogilvy 22:00, 1996 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-018)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Advertising Women of New York, 1998 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-019)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Advertising Women of New York Lifetime Achiev ement, 1997 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-020)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--American Express, Harvey Golub Brand Film, 1996 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-021)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Brand Stewardship Charlotte Beers commercials, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-022)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Brandprint with Jaguar and Dove, 24:00, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-023)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Charlotte Beers/A. Papone conversation with cuts to American Express TRS meeting: A Case Study of Brand, 1994 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-024)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Charlotte Beers Answers Your Questions, 1992 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-025)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Charlotte Beets reel, WPP Security Analysts Meeting, 1994 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-026)
    Includes: American Express--Chiat/Day "Plane"; Balestreri; Hermes; Conrans; Harvey Golub. IBM. American Express Brand Stewardship Film
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Presentation for United Airlines, 1996 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-027)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--The Dittmer's 30th, 1996 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-028)
  - Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing: American Public Diplomacy and Islam; Charlotte Beers and Kenneth Tomlinson, tape 1 of 2; 90:00, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-029)
  - Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing: American Public Diplomacy and Islam; Charlotte Beers and Kenneth Tomlinson, tape 2 of 2; 90:00, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-030)
  - Tatham RSCG--Happy Trails Charlotte, 1992 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-031)
  - This Week with Cookie Roberts, Meet the Press, 2002 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-032)
  - Tom Friedman and Hisham Melham address the Global PAO Symposium, 2002 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-033)
  - Under Secretary Beers--USAID Natsios: Public Diplomacy and Foreign Aid tape 1, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-034)
  - Under Secretary Charlotte Beers--NPC news conference, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-035)
  - Under Secretary Charlotte Beers--Remarks before ACVFA Public Diplomacy in the National Interest, 28:00`, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-036)
  - Under Secretary Charlotte Beers and Kenneth Tomlinson--Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing: American Public Diplomacy and Islam, tape 1, TRT 1:22:36, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-037)
  - Under Secretary Charlotte Beers and Kenneth Tomlinson--Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing: American Public Diplomacy and Islam, tape 2, TRT 1:22:36, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-038)
  - WomenFuture Main Event: Charlotte Beers, 32:00, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-039)
  - Women's Forum, remarks by Beers, 2nd copy, 32:00, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-040)
  - Women's Leadership Exchange Atlanta 2004 Conference; Georgia Business Report, Georgia Public Television (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-VHS-041)
  - For Evan: Copy of Charlotte Beers' DVD, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-Bcam-001)
  - Steve Kessler, Charlotte Beers source tape 01, 2009 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-Bcam-002)
    Includes: Fortune Women's Conference 2002; Television interviews ABC, Fox, NBC; Tatham RSCG "Happy Trails Charlotte"; Brandprint senior office meeting; Case study of brand Amex; Good Morning America and Harvard video; Tribute to David Ogilvy
  - Charlotte Beers Yahoo! Interview, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11767-DVCAM-001)
  - Ogilvy & Mather--Advertising on Ogilvy, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11767-Umatic-001)
  - AAF Advertising Hall of Fame, 2009 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-001)
  - AAF Introduction Film, 2009 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-002)
  - AAF Raleigh-Durham--An Intimate Tea with Charlotte Beers, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-003)
  - ABC, Fox News, NBC clips, [1992] (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-004)
  - ACVFA Public Diplomacy Remarks, 2003 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-005)
  - Advertising Council dinner reel, 16:00, 1994 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-006)
  - Advertising Hall of Fame, 2009 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-007)
  - Advertising Hall of Fame, 2009 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-008)
  - Advertising on Ogilvy, 1996 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-009)
  - Advertising on Ogilvy edited, 1996 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-010)
  - Advertising Women of New York Lifetime Achievement, 1997 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-011)
  - American Express spots, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-012)
  - Base presentation--Powell interview and other materials used in speeches, 2002 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-013)
  - C-Span, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-014)
  - Career Camp Bites--Mock interviews, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-015)
  - CEO Bootcamp, undated (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-016)
  - CEO Bootcamp, 2013 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-017)
  - Cheryl Woodruff track 1, 2007 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-018)
  - Cheryl Woodruff track 2, 2007 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-019)
  - Charlotte and Cheryl--Charlotte Goes to Washington, 2007 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11767-OP-020)